Speaker: Experts agree that getting up early is a big help if you have a lot of things to do.
There are three main reasons for this.
The first reason why it’s good to get up early is that the early morning is quiet.
Nobody phones you at 6.00 a.m.
There aren’t any important emails or messages to answer.
There aren’t any meetings.
There aren’t any people.
The morning is your time.
The second reason is that if you get up early, you go to bed early.
Most people don’t do anything useful in the evenings.
People who go to bed late spend many hours watching TV,
seeing their friends, and spending time on social media.
So if you want to do a lot, it’s better to go to bed early,
and have shorter evenings and longer mornings.
The third reason is that it’s better to do things in the morning, when you have energy.
Most people are tired after a day at work or college.
And when you’re tired, the last thing you want to do is to exercise,
or to study, or to practise a musical instrument.
And if you find it impossible to get up early?
Set your alarm five minutes earlier than you usually get up.
And the next day set it five minutes earlier again.
After three weeks you’ll have nearly two hours that you never had before!